Guide to the Felix S. Cohen Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Legal Career, 1931-1953; Series I; 29; (57 boxes)
  - PRIVATE PRACTICE OFFICE RECORDS
    - Marks & Marks [Phoenix law firm], 1948-49 (Box 52, Folder 791)
    - Migratory agriculture labor legislation, 1950-52 (Box 52, Folder 792-96)
      See also: Oversize, Box 100, folder 1624
    - New York Association for New Americans, 1949-50 (Box 52, Folder 797-806)
    - New York Association for New Americans, 1948-53, n.d. (Box 53, Folder 807-08)
    - Osage Nation vs. United States of America, 1949 Oct (Box 53, Folder 809)
    - Paul, William (Alaska General), 1948 (Box 53, Folder 810)
    - Powell, Mrs. Emma, 1949 (Box 53, Folder 811)
    - [Pueblo Social Security Case - Press release], 1947 Jun 17 (Box 53, Folder 812)
    - Revels, Linzy, 1950 (Box 53, Folder 813)
    - Singer, Rita (Alaska) [lawyer worked for Curry, [H.] Cohen, & Bingham], 1948 (Box 53, Folder 814)
    - Weihofen, Henry [lawyer Cohen worked with], 1948-49 (Box 53, Folder 815)
      See also: Box 50, folder 759
    - Weisz, Morris, 1952-55,1982 (Box 53, Folder 816)
    - Wertheim & Company - Bristol-Myers Corporation, 1952, 1982 (Box 53, Folder 817)
    - Westenhaver, Esther, 1948, 1982 (Box 53, Folder 818)
    - Wilkinson, Ernest L. [attorney Cohen worked with], 1946-50 (Box 53, Folder 819)
    - Wright, C. M. [attorney Cohen worked with], 1948-49 (Box 53, Folder 820)
    - Travel, 1948-52 (Box 53, Folder 821-26)
    - Time sheets, 1947-48 (Box 53, Folder 827-34)
    - Time sheets, 1948-50 (Box 54, Folder 835-56)
      See also: Oversize, Box 101, folders 1643-44
    - Time sheets, 1950-52 (Box 55, Folder 857-77)
      See also: Oversize, Box 101, folder 1645
    - Time sheets, 1952-53 (Box 56, Folder 878-96)
    - Daily notes, 1948 (Box 57, Folder 897-904)
    - Chronological [correspondence], 1950 Nov (Box 57, Folder 905-06)
    - Monthly Time Records 1948, 1947-48 (Box 57, Folder 907)
    - Time records, 1948-49 (Box 57, Folder 908)
      See also: Oversize, Box 101, folder 1646
    - Time records - monthly totals (by subject), 1948-52 (Box 57, Folder 909)
      See also: Oversize, Box 101, folder 1647
    - Time records - monthly (FSC)
      See: Oversize, Box 101, folder 1648
    - Time records - monthly
      See: Oversize, Box 101, folder 1649
- Teaching Career, 1946-1953; Series II; 1.5; (4 boxes)
  Series II contains material from courses Cohen taught at Yale University's Law School and The City College of New York's Philosophy Department. Material related to students is restricted. The files have been arranged by university, course, and semester.
  See also: Box 72-74, folders 1148-87
  - MATERIAL FOR YALE AND CCNY
    - Yale-CCNY material on jurisprudence, 1948-49, n.d. (Box 58, Folder 910)
    - Cohen's class notes for jurisprudence course, 1949-52 (Box 58, Folder 911-13)
    - Cohen's class notes for 1950 jurisprudence course, ca. 1950 (Box 58, Folder 914-15)
  - YALE COURSES
    - General
      - Correspondence, 1947-50 (Box 58, Folder 916-17)
      - Bulletin of Yale University. Law School, 1947-49, 1949 Sep (Box 58, Folder 918)
    - Legislative Drafting Seminar
      - Correspondence, 1946 (Box 58, Folder 919-20)
        See also: Oversize, Box 100, folder 1625
      - Cohen's class notes, ca. 1946 (Box 58, Folder 921-22)
      - Legislative reports and bills prepared by students, 1946, n.d. (Box 58, Folder 923)
      - Legislative reports and bills prepared by students, 1946, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 924-29)
      - Schedule and miscellaneous papers, ca. 1946 (Box 59, Folder 930)
    - Jurisprudence class
      - [Spring term 1948]: miscellaneous, 1948, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 931)
      - Spring term 1948: student papers, 1948, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 932)
      - Fall term 1948: correspondence (Box 59, Folder 933)
      - Fall term 1948: miscellaneous, ca. 1948 (Box 59, Folder 934)
      - Spring term 1949: correspondence and miscellaneous, ca. 1948 (Box 59, Folder 935)
      - Fall term 1950: correspondence, 1950-51 (Box 59, Folder 936-37)
      - Fall term 1950: student paper, ca. 1951 (Box 59, Folder 938)
      - Fall term 1950: final exam questions, ca. 1951 Feb (Box 60, Folder 939)
      - Writing Projects, 1916-53; Series III; 6.5; (15 boxes)
        Series III has been arranged by type of material, Book Reviews, Articles, Addresses, Books and Pamphlets, and Works by Others; within each grouping titles are arranged alphabetically.
        - GENERAL
          - Correspondence regarding publications, 1949-53, n.d. (Box 62, Folder 966)
        - BOOK REVIEWS
          - Invitations to write reviews, 1950-53 (Box 62, Folder 967-68)
            Similar correspondence for 1935-40, see Box 41, folder 1209, and for 1939-50, see Boxes 57-58, folders 511-519
          - Monroe Berger's Equality by Statute, 1952-53 (Box 62, Folder 969)
          - Edmond M. Cahn's The Sense of Injustice, 1950 (Box 62, Folder 970)
          - Huntington Cairns's Legal Philosophy from Plato to Hegel, 1941, 1949 (Box 62, Folder 971)
          - Walter F. Dodd's Administration of Workmen's Compensation, 1937 (Box 62, Folder 972)
          - Grant Foreman's The American Indian and the Law, 1952 (Box 62, Folder 973)
            No draft or copy of the review.
          - Osmond K. Fraenkel's Our Civil Liberties, 1944-45 (Box 62, Folder 974)
          - Milton Konvitz's Civil Rights in Immigration, 1946, 1953 (Box 62, Folder 975)
          - Milton Konvitz's The Alien and the Asiatic in American Law
            See: Box 62, folder 975 and Box 87, folder 1385
          - President's Committee on Civil Rights, To Secure these Rights
            See: Box 63, folders 1002-05
          - Julius Rosenthal Foundation's My Philosophy of Law, 1939-43 (Box 62, Folder 976)
          - Clarence Irving Lewis's Analysis of Knowledge and Valuation, 1948 (Box 62, Folder 977)
          - Samuel Mermin, 1949 (Box 62, Folder 978)
          - Alexander Pekelis's Law and Social Action, 1951-52 (Box 62, Folder 979-80)
          - Karl S. Popper Open Society and its Enemies, 1951 (Box 62, Folder 981)
          - Julius Stone's The Province and Function of Law, 1948-49 (Box 62, Folder 982)
          - Book reviews by others, 1949-52, n.d. (Box 62, Folder 983)
        - ARTICLES
          - Correspondence, 1939-48 (Box 62, Folder 984)
          - Correspondence with law reviews, 1939-50 (Box 62, Folder 985-86)
          - Correspondence with law reviews, 1939-50 (Box 63, Folder 987-92)
          - Suggestions for future articles, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 993)
          - "Abolishing the Indian Bureau," earlier title for "Colonialism: U.S. Style"
            See: Box 63, folders 1006-09
          - "Alaska's Nuremberg Laws," Commentary, 1941-50 (Box 63, Folder 994-95)
          - Americanizing our Immigration Laws, 1949-52 (Box 63, Folder 996-99)
          - "Americanizing the White Man," All- Indian Pow-Wow, 1952 July (Box 63, Folder 1000)
            See also: Box 10, folder 145
          - "Anthropology and the Problems of Indian Administration," The Southwestern Social Science Quarterly, 1937 (Box 63, Folder 1001)
            See also: Box 1, folders 7-10
          - "The Civil Rights Report," Etc: A Review of General Semantics, 1947-49 (Box 63, Folder 1002-05)
          - "Cohen Raps Alaska Colonialism: Government, Industry Both Blamed," Alaska Federationist. v. 3, no. 15 (Juneau, Alaska)
            See: Oversize, Box 100, folder 1620
          - "Colonialism: A Realistic Approach," Ethics, ca. 1945 (Box 63, Folder 1005)
          - "Colonialism: U.S. Style," Progressive, 1942-51 (Box 63, Folder 1006-09)
          - "Communist Double Talk," New Leader, 1953 (Box 63, Folder 1010)
          - "Communist Double Talk," New Leader, 1953 (Box 64, Folder 1011)
          - Derecho Indigena: Contribucion Espanola al Sistema Legal de Los Estados Unidos. The National Indian Institute, Department of the Interior, 1942 (Spanish translation of "The Spanish Origin of Indian Rights...")
            See: Box 10, folders 142-48
          - "Dialogue on Private Property," Rutgers Law Review, 1954 (Box 64, Folder 1012-14)
            See also: Box 91, folder 1469
          - Dictionary of Social Sciences, 1941 (Box 64, Folder 1015)
            No draft or copy of the article
          - "The Erosion of Indian Rights, 1950-53: A Case Study of Bureaucracy," Yale Law Journal, 1952-53 (Box 64, Folder 1016-26)
          - "Experiment in Immortality," The Nation, 1952 (Box 64, Folder 1027)
          - "Field Theory and Judicial Logic," Yale Law Journal, 1926, 1949-52 (Box 64, Folder 1028)
          - "Field Theory and Judicial Logic," Yale Law Journal, 1926, 1949-52 (Box 65, Folder 1029-32)
          - "First Americans First," The New Leader, 1952-53 (Box 65, Folder 1033-34)
          - "The Great Salmon Swindle," unpublished article co-authored with Harold L. Ickes, 1948 (Box 65, Folder 1035)
            See also: Box 28, folder 454
          - "Harold L. Ickes, The Champion of the Disposed," Freeland, 1952 (Box 65, Folder 1036)
          - "The Holmes-Cohen Correspondence," Journal of the History of Ideas, 1948 Jan (Box 65, Folder 1037)
            See also: Box 87, folder 1376; Box 88, folder 1404; and Box 89, folder 1434
          - "How Long Will Indian Constitutions Last?" Indians at Work
            See: Box 1, folder 3
          - "How We Bought the United States," Collier's, ca. 1944-46 (Box 65, Folder 1038-42)
          - Immigration and National Welfare, League for Industrial Democracy
            See: Box 67-68, folders 1072-88
          - Immigration article prepared for Pennsylvania Law Review but never completed, 1952-53 (Box 65, Folder 1043)
          - "The Indian Bureau Record: 1950-1952"
            See: "The Erosion of Indian Rights, 1950-53: A Case Study of Bureaucracy," Box 64, folders 1016-26
          - "Indian Claims," The American Indian, 1945 (Box 65, Folder 1044-45)
          - "The Indian Land Problem," for the Hoover Commission, 1948-49 (Box 65, Folder 1046)
          - "Indian Rights and the Federal Courts," Minnesota Law Review, 1939-48 (Box 66, Folder 1047-52)
          - "Indian Self-Government," The American Indian, 1935-50 (Box 66, Folder 1053-56)
          - "Indian Wardship: the Twilight of a Myth," The American Indian, 1953 (Box 66, Folder 1057)
          - "Indians are Citizens," The American Indian, 1944 (Box 66, Folder 1058)
            See also: Box 2, folders 25-28
          - "Invisible Indian Resources," unpublished article
            See: Box 1, folder 5
          - "Legal Status of the Indian in the United States," prepared for the 1st Interamerican Indian Congress, 1939-42 (Box 66, Folder 1059-60)
          - "Mythology of Immigration" or "The Myth of the Immigration Scare"
            See: Box 70, folder 1110-16
          - "The Myth of Puerto Rican Overpopulation," News Letter of the Institute of Ethnic Affairs, 1947 (Box 67, Folder 1061)
          - "Natural and Human Resources"
            Probably by Felix S. Cohen.
            Related Materials
            See: Box 32, folder 501
          - "The Navajo, the Eskimo, and the Marshall Plan"
            See: Box 28, folder 455
          - "Open Season of Alaskan Natives," News Letter of the Institute of Ethnic Affairs, 1948 (Box 67, Folder 1062)
          - "Original Indian Title," Minnesota Law Review, 1933-46, n.d. (Box 67, Folder 1063)
          - "Our Country's Shame," Progressive, 1948-49 (Box 67, Folder 1064)
          - "'Overpopulation' of Puerto Rico," The Socialist Call, Oct 24, 1947
            See also: Box 30, folders 478-479
          - "The People v. Discrimination," Commentary, 1945-49, n.d. (Box 67, Folder 1065-66)
          - "Puerto Rico's Problem: Colonialism"
          - Philosophy of law articles, 1940-48, n.d. (Box 67, Folder 1067-68)
          - "Policing the Indians," New Republic, 1952 (Box 67, Folder 1069)
          - "Recent Indian Progress Towards Equality," Nairo Reporter, 1951, 1953 (Box 67, Folder 1070)
          - "The Relativity of Philosophical Systems and the Method of Systematic Relativism," Journal of Philosophy, 1939 (Box 67, Folder 1071)
          - "Science and Politics in Plans for Puerto Rico," Journal of Social Issues, Fall 1947
            See: Box 31, folder 496-99
          - "The Social and Economic Consequences of Exclusionary Immigration Laws," National Lawyers Guild Quarterly and Immigration and National Welfare, League for Industrial Democracy, 1939-41 (Box 67, Folder 1072-76)
          - "The Social and Economic Consequences of Exclusionary Immigration Laws," National Lawyers Guild Quarterly and Immigration and National Welfare, League for Industrial Democracy, 1939-41 (Box 68, Folder 1077-84)
          - "The Social and Economic Consequences of Exclusionary Immigration Laws," National Lawyers Guild Quarterly and Immigration and National Welfare, League for Industrial Democracy, 1939-41 (Box 68, Folder 1085-88)
          - "The Socialization of Morality," American Philosophy Today and Tomorrow, [1935] (Box 68, Folder 1089)
          - "The Spanish Origin of Indian Rights in the Law of the United States," Georgetown Law Journal, 1940-43, n.d. (Box 68, Folder 1090-92)
            See also: Box 1, folder 1
          - "The Subject Matter of Ethical Science," The International Journal of Ethics, 1932 Jul (Box 68, Folder 1093)
          - "What City College Will Contribute to the Development of the Law," The Barrister, 1938 (Box 69, Folder 1094)
            See also: Box 71, folder 1137-39
          - "What is a Question?" The Monist, 1929 Jul (Box 69, Folder 1095)
        - ADDRESSES
          - "Americanism and Immigration," Brooklyn Society for Ethical Culture, 1949-50 (Box 69, Folder 1096)
          - "America's Minorities: The Administrative Record", 1943-44 (Box 69, Folder 1097-99)
          - "American's Minorities - The Administrative Record", 1943-44 (Box 69, Folder 1100)
            See also: Oversize, Box 101, folder 1650
          - "Breaking Faith with our First Americans," 65th Annual Meeting of the Indian Rights Association, published in Indian Truth, 1948-49 (Box 69, Folder 1101)
          - "Democracy and the War", 1942-51, n.d. (Box 69, Folder 1102-06)
            See also: Oversize, Box 100, folder 1626
          - "The Democratic Faith in 1951," Yale Philosophy Club (Box 69, Folder 1107-09)
          - "The Economics of Refugee Immigration," National Refugee Service Inc. Annual Meeting, January 21 1945 and "Mythology of Immigration", 1945-47 (Box 70, Folder 1110-16)
          - "Ethics of Our Foreign Policy," University of Texas Great Issues Class, 1951-52 (Box 70, Folder 1117)
            No draft or copy of the address.
            See also: Oversize, Box 101, folder 1651
          - "Government and the Social Contract"
            See: Box 74, folder 1186
          - "Human Rights: An Appeal to Philosophers," Eastern Division of APA's symposium "The Concept of Universal Human Rights", 1951-53 (Box 70, Folder 1118-20)
          - "Jerome Michael: A Student's Homage," Cohen's remarks at Michael's funeral service, later published with others work in "Jerome Michael," Columbia Law Review, 1953 (Box 70, Folder 1121)
          - "Judicial Ethics," Ohio State Law University symposium "Ethical Values and the Law in Action," published Ohio State Law Journal, 1951 (Box 70, Folder 1122-24)
            See also: Box 71, folder 1130
          - "Judicial Ethics," Ohio State Law University symposium "Ethical Values and the Law in Action," published Ohio State Law Journal, 1949-52 (Box 71, Folder 1125)
          - "Law and Language," Riccobono Seminar of Roman Law in America, Catholic University Law School, 1945, 1949 (Box 71, Folder 1126)
          - "The Meaning of Americanism", 1953 (Box 71, Folder 1127)
          - "The Menace of Government Experts," CCNY Government - Law Society, 1953 (Box 71, Folder 1128)
          - "Mythology of Immigration"
            See: Box 70, folders 1110-16
          - Poll Tax "A Challenge to America", 1946 (Box 71, Folder 1129)
          - "The Relationship between Ethics and Law," Columbia University Law School, 1949-50 (Box 71, Folder 1130)
            See also: Box 70-71, folders 1122-25 and Oversize, Box 100, folder 1627
          - "The Role of Science in Government," American Association for the Advancement of Science Annual Meeting, published in Social Science, 1935-47, n.d. (Box 71, Folder 1131-36)
          - "Urbs Coronata: The College and the City, CCNY Phi Beta Kappa Chapter, 1938, 1948-49 (Box 71, Folder 1137-39)
          - Miscellaneous, 1949-50 (Box 71, Folder 1140)
        - BOOKS AND PAMPHLETS
          - Combatting Totalitarian Propaganda: A Legal Reappraisal. Washington, D.C.: Institute of Living Law
            See: Box 79, folder 1248
          - Ethical Systems and Legal Ideals. Westport, Connecticut: Greenwood Press, 1976 (Box 71.1, Folder 1141)
          - Felix S. Cohen's Handbook of Federal Indian Law 1982 Edition. edited by Rennard Strickland. Charlottesville, Virginia: Miche Bobbs-Merrill (Box 71.2, Folder 1142)
          - Handbook of Federal Indian Law. Washington: United States Government Printing Office, 1941 (Box 72.1, Folder 1143)
          - The Legal Conscience
            No draft or copy of the book.
            - Draft bibliography, n.d. (Box 72, Folder 1144)
            - Review by William O. Douglas reprinted in the Congressional Record, 1961 Mar 28 (Box 72, Folder 1145)
            - Review by Samuel J. Konefsky, 1961 Mar 5 (Box 72, Folder 1146)
            - Review by Alexander M. Bickel, 1961 Apr 24 (Box 72, Folder 1147)
          - "The Powers of an Indian Tribe"
            See: Box 8, folder 112
          - Readings in Jurisprudence and Legal Philosophy
            See also: Box 88, folder 1397
            - Revised edition by Philip Shuchman Boston and Toronto: Little, Brown and Company, 1979 (Box 72.2, Folder 1148)
            - "Readings for a Course in the Philosophy of Law," syllabus for College of the City of New York, 1948, n.d. (Box 72, Folder 1149-55)
            - "Readings for a Course in the Philosophy of Law," syllabus for College of the City of New York, 1948, n.d. (Box 73, Folder 1156-60)
            - Untitled draft A, n.d. (Box 73, Folder 1161)
            - Untitled draft B, 1927-41, n.d. (Box 73, Folder 1162-67)
            - "Source Book" draft A, 1933-48, n.d. (Box 74, Folder 1168-73)
            - "Source Book" draft A, 1916, 1928, n.d. (Box 74, Folder 1174-77)
            - "Source Book" draft B, n.d. (Box 74, Folder 1178)
            - "Syllabus" draft, n.d. (Box 74, Folder 1179-82)
            - "Duplicate pages", n.d. (Box 74, Folder 1183)
            - "Addenda to first twelve chapters" (Box 74, Folder 1184)
            - "Law and Politics" chp. 4 (Box 74, Folder 1185)
            - "Readings: Bibliography legenda", 1938-50, n.d. (Box 74, Folder 1186)
            - "Law and Economics" draft, 1937-50, n.d. (Box 74, Folder 1187)
            - "Readings addenda" (Box 75, Folder 1188)
            - Correspondence with Prentice-Hall (publishers of 1st edition), 1950-53 (Box 75, Folder 1189)
            - Correspondence with Prentice-Hall (publishers of 1st edition), 1950-53 (Box 75, Folder 1190-92)
            - Correspondence regarding distribution (especially CCNY and Yale), 1948-51, n.d. (Box 75, Folder 1193-97)
            - Correspondence requesting permission to include works in Readings, 1951 (Box 75, Folder 1198-99)
            - Correspondence requesting permission to include works in Readings, 1952 (Box 76, Folder 1200)
            - Orders and distribution of gift copies (includes printed version with corrections), 1951-52, n.d. (Box 76, Folder 1201-03)
            - Publicity, 1951-53 (Box 76, Folder 1204)
            - Accounts, royalty payments from Prentice-Hall, 1952-53 (Box 76, Folder 1205)
        - WORKS BY OTHERS
          - Secretary Krug's, "Effective Communication of Ideas," talk at Reed College, 1947 (Box 76, Folder 1206)
          - "Noble Red Man - American Indians Are Tired of Being Treated Like Irresponsible Children," by Fred Theroux, 1952 (Box 76, Folder 1207)
            See also: Oversize, Box 101, folder 1652
          - "El Arte del Indio en los Estados Unidos," by Rene D'Harnoncourt, 1943 (Box 76, Folder 1208)
      - Fall term 1950: miscellaneous, 1950-51 (Box 60, Folder 940)
      - Fall term 1951: correspondence, 1950-52 (Box 60, Folder 941)
      - Fall term 1951: notes and final exam questions, 1952 Jan (Box 60, Folder 942)
      - Fall term 1952: correspondence, 1951-53 (Box 60, Folder 943-44)
      - Fall term 1952: student paper, [1953 Jan] (Box 60, Folder 945)
      - Fall term 1952: miscellaneous, 1951-52 (Box 60, Folder 946)
      - Fall term 1953: correspondence, 1952-53 (Box 60, Folder 947)
      - Fall term 1953: Dialogue on Private Property, 1st lecture of semester never delivered
        See: Box 64, folders 1012-14
  - CCNY COURSES
    - General
      - Correspondence, 1948-53 (Box 60, Folder 948-54)
    - Philosophy of law
      - Spring term 1948: correspondence (Box 60, Folder 955)
      - Spring term 1948: student papers, 1948 May (Box 60, Folder 956)
      - Spring term 1949: notes (Box 60, Folder 957)
      - Spring term 1949: student evaluations (Box 61, Folder 958)
      - Spring term 1949: The Campus, student newspaper, 1949 Mar (Box 61, Folder 959)
      - Spring term 1949: miscellaneous, ca. 1949 (Box 61, Folder 960)
      - Fall term 1950: notes and miscellaneous, 1951 (Box 61, Folder 961)
      - Fall term 1950: student papers, 1950-51 (Box 61, Folder 962)
      - Fall term 1951: correspondence, 1951-52 (Box 61, Folder 963)
      - Fall term 1952: student papers, 1953 (Box 61, Folder 964)
      - Fall term 1952: final questions, 1953 Jan (Box 61, Folder 965)
- Collegial - Institutional Affiliations, 1935-1953; Series IV; 3.75; (9 boxes)
  The series is divided into two subseries, Institute of Living Law and Other Organizations, where groups are listed alphabetically.
  - INSTITUTE OF LIVING LAW
    - General
      - Documents regarding foundation, 1940-42 (Box 77, Folder 1209)
      - Minutes and reports, 1941, 1944 (Box 77, Folder 1210)
      - Correspondence, 1941-51 (Box 77, Folder 1211-12)
      - Institute's publications, 1940-46, n.d. (Box 77, Folder 1213-14)
      - Background material, 1933-47, n.d. (Box 77, Folder 1215-21)
      - Miscellaneous, 1942-54, n.d. (Box 77, Folder 1222)
    - Legislative Projects
      - Administrative Law, 1939-41 (Box 77, Folder 1223)
      - Administrative Law, 1939-41, n.d. (Box 78, Folder 1224-25)
      - Articles of War, 1946 (Box 78, Folder 1226-28)
      - Foreign Agent Registration Act, 1941-42 (Box 78, Folder 1229-33)
      - Full Employment Bill, 1945 (Box 78, Folder 1234-36)
      - Pacific Charter and colonialism, 1942-45, n.d. (Box 78, Folder 1237-38)
        See also: Oversize, Box 100, folder 1628
      - Pacific Charter and colonialism, 1942-45, n.d. (Box 79, Folder 1239-41)
      - Propaganda exposure, 1939-43 (Box 79, Folder 1242-45)
      - Selective Service Training Act, 1941 (Box 79, Folder 1246)
    - "Handbook of Propaganda Warfare"
      - First edition published in law reviews, 1942-43 (Box 79, Folder 1247)
      - Combatting Totalitarian Propaganda: A Legal Reappraisal. Washington, D.C.: Institute of Living Law (two copies), 1944 (Box 79, Folder 1248)
      - Draft forward to Combatting Totalitarian Propaganda: A Legal Reappraisal, ca. 1944 (Box 80, Folder 1249)
      - Draft of "Handbook of Propaganda Warfare," the work as originally planned by the Institute, ca. 1940 (Box 80, Folder 1250-54)
      - Various drafts, labeled A-I, ca. 1944, n.d. (Box 80, Folder 1255-63)
      - Various drafts, labeled J-M, ca. 1942, n.d. (Box 81, Folder 1264-67)
      - Various drafts, chapter 1, n.d. (Box 81, Folder 1268)
      - Various drafts, chapter 2, n.d. (Box 81, Folder 1269)